SHAKIB NIHAN KARIM

Cell: +1(347)-279-2504 | E-mail: nihan66@yahoo.com | New York, NY 11416 Portfolio: shakib-karim.netlify.com || Github: https://github.com/snihank Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/shakib-nihan-karim-7715b29

SUMMARY

Passionate Full Stack Developer adept at building sophisticated user-friendly web and mobile applications, with a life-long dedication to learning. Specializing in MERN and Java full stack development and Test automation. Prioritizes quality work under strict deadlines, and successfully collaborates with management and peers; bringing great ability to adapt to ever-changing technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript | Java | HTML5 | CSS3 | Bootstrap | React | Redux | Handlebars | jQuery | AJAX | Node.js | SQL | NoSQL | UNIX/LINUX Commmand Line | MySQL | MongoDB | Firebase | Postgres | Spring Boot | Hibernate | JDBC Template | JPA | Swagger API | JUNIT | TDD | BDD | Agile | Scrum | SDLC | Express | Axios | Cheerio | Mocha | Chai | Postman | Maven | Cucumber | Appium | Selenium | Git | Github | Gitlab | Pivotal Tracker | JIRA | Trello | Coggle | Heroku | Netlify | Jenkins | Unit Testing | Regression Testing |

EDUCATION | TRAINING

Columbia Engineering Coding Certificate (2019) Columbia University, New York, NY, USA

Graduate Certificate in Business (2016) University of Western Sydney, Sydney, Australia

Bachelors in Business Administration (2008) North South University, Dhaka, Bangladesh

PROJECTS

Google Books Search | Code: github.com/snihank/google-books | Demo:

This application enables users to search books using Google Books API, save and delete them.

Role: Sole Developer

Utilized: Javascript, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Google Books API, Node.js, Heroku

NYT Article Search | Code: github.com/snihank/Scrape-Mongo | Demo:

An application scraping articles The New York Times website and saving them to database.

Role: Sole Developer

Utilized: Javascript, ¡Query, Handlebars.js, MongoDB, Express.js. Cheerio, Heroku.

Continued...

Shakib Nihan Karim, Page 2

Hotels.com || Code: https://github.com/snihank/seleniumHotelsWebProject ||

This is a regression testing project of the website Hotels.com.

Role: Sole Developer

Utilized: Java, Selenium Webdriver, Maven, BDD Approach, Cucumber and Gherkins.

React Memory Game || Code: https://github.com/snihank/clicky-game || Demo:

Role: Sole Developer

In this memory game users have a group of images to click, not clicking the same image twice.

Role: Sole Developer

Utilized: React, React DOM, npm and node.

Liri-Bot || Code: https://github.com/snihank/liri-node-app

A command line application where users can quickly and easily find information about concerts,

movies and favorite songs from external third party APIs.

Role: Sole Developer

Utilized: Axios, fs, node-spotify-api, omdbapi api, command line etc.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Trilogy Education Services

July 2019 - Present

UCONN School of Engineering, University Of Connecticut

Teaching Assistant, Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Educating students in HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery, React, MySQL, MongoDB, AJAX, JSON, Handlebars, etc. Checking coding assignments, conducting in class coding challenges, uploading class materials in gitlab, helping students in understanding code, conducting office hours lectures on problem areas such as object-oriented programming, javascript, jQuery, React, databases, etc.

Swissport USA Inc, JFK Airport, New York, USA Passenger Service Agent, Kuwait Airways

May 2017 - January 2019

UNICEF Australia, NSW, Sydney, Australia Team Lead, Face to Face Team

September 2016 - October 2016

Team Lead, Face to Face Team

UNHCR Australia, NSW, Sydney, Australia Senior Frontliner, Face to Face Team July 2015 - April 2016

The ACME Agrovet & Beverages Ltd, Dhaka, Bangladesh Brand Team Lead, Brand & Marketing Department

April 2008 - June 2015